dodo.com 2019-05-04

# Privacy Policy

Dodo Group of
Companies
Privacy
Policy

Dodo Group of Companies
Privacy Policy
The Dodo Group (Dodo, we us, our) comprises Dodo Australia Holdings
Pty Ltd, Dodo Group Services Pty Ltd, Dodo Insurance Pty Ltd, M2 Energy
Pty Ltd (trading as Dodo Power & Gas) and Dodo Services Pty Ltd and
Secureway Pty Ltd. The Dodo companies are members of the Vocus
Group, being wholly owned subsidiaries of Vocus Group Ltd.
Dodo provides internet, mobile, telephone, electricity and gas,
and insurance products and services, predominately to residential
customers. Dodo is committed to protecting the privacy and personal
information of its customers. This Privacy Policy describes the practices
and processes Dodo has in place to properly manage and safeguard that
information.
Privacy laws that apply to Dodo
Dodo is required to comply with the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and is bound
by the Australian Privacy Principles (‘APPs’) set out in that Act. The APPs
establish minimum standards for the collection, use, disclosure and
handling of personal information. They apply to personal information in
any form, including electronic and digital form. The APPs can be accessed
at the website of the office of the Australian Information Commissioner:
www.privacy.gov.au.
Dodo is also subject to other laws relating to the protection of
personal information. Where Dodo provides telecommunications
carriage services, it is subject to privacy obligations under the
Telecommunications Act 1997 (Cth). Where Dodo provides electricity
and gas, Dodo may be subject to requirements relating to the privacy
of retail customer information. Dodo’s direct marketing activities must
also comply with the Do Not Call Register Act 2006 (Cth) and the Spam
Act 2010 (Cth). If Dodo collects health information, it may be required to
comply with statutory requirements relating to health records.
In this Privacy Policy, unless the context otherwise requires:
 • ‘Privacy Law’ refers to any legislative or other legal requirement that
    applies to Dodo’s collection, use, disclosure or handling of personal
    information.
 • ‘Personal information’ means information or an opinion about an
    identified individual or an individual who is reasonably identifiable,
    whether the information or opinion is true or not and whether the
    information or opinion is recorded in material form or not. Personal
    information includes sensitive information.
 • ‘Sensitive information’ means personal information about an
    individual’s racial or ethnic origin, political opinions or memberships,
    religious beliefs or affiliations, philosophical beliefs, professional
    or trade association/union memberships, sexual preferences and
    practices or criminal record.
Why does Dodo collect personal information?
Dodo collects personal information in order to:
 • manage and administer the products and services we provide,
    including for billing and credit control purposes;
 • inform customers about changes and improvements in Dodo
    products and services;
1.

 • market Dodo products and services to current and prospective
    customers;
 • market third party products and services to current and prospective
    customers; and
 • comply with our legal obligations.
Dodo needs to be able to collect personal information for most of its
business activities, although the information we require depends on
the particular circumstances. If we are unable to collect the personal
information we need, we may be unable to meet the expectations of our
customers or provide the products and services they wish to receive.
Whose personal information does Dodo collect?
Dodo collects or holds personal information about individuals who are:
 • Prospective customers. This includes people we think may be
    interested in our products and services as well as people who
    have expressed interest in obtaining or learning more about those
    products and services.
 • Current customers. This includes people who purchase Dodo
    products or services or who hold an account with Dodo.
 • Past customers. These are people who have purchased Dodo
    products or services but do not currently hold any active Dodo
    account.
Dodo may treat current and past customers as prospective customers for
other Dodo products and services.
Dodo may collect personal information about associates of its
customers, such as family members, employees or agents. For example,
Dodo may collect personal information about nominated or authorised
representatives, the holder of a credit card that is used to pay a
customer’s account, a person who acts as a secondary account holder,
a person who acts as guarantor for a credit contract, the landlord of a
tenanted property or the nominated contact on a business account.
Dodo may in rare circumstances collect personal information from
people who are under the age of 18. If Dodo does this, Dodo may also
collect personal information about the parent or guardian of that person.
Dodo also collects personal information about all the individuals who
are involved in providing Dodo products and services. This includes:
 • staff of Dodo Group entities and other companies in the Vocus group;
    and
 • service providers and suppliers, agents and affiliates, and their staff.
Can you deal with Dodo without identifying yourself?
In some limited situations customers and other individuals may be able
to deal with Dodo anonymously or using a pseudonym. For example, if
you make a general inquiry to one of our call centres, or want to make a
complaint or log a service fault unless the inquiry or complaint relates to
a particular account.
However, if you do not wish to be identified we may not be able to provide
the information or assistance you require.
                                                                          2.

What personal information does Dodo usually collect?
Dodo collects a wide range of personal information about its customers,
but the type and amount of information collected depends on the
particular business context. However, Dodo seeks at all times to ensure
that it only collects the personal information that is necessary for the
purposes of its business activities.
Dodo needs to collect basic identifying and contact information for all
customers, including prospective customers. This will usually include
name, date of birth, email address, telephone number(s) and residential
address. For corporate and business customers, Dodo collects
information about nominated contacts, including name and title or
position, date of birth, telephone number(s) and email and business
addresses.
Dodo also collects information about purchasing patterns, consumer
preferences and attitudes from prospective and current customers for
marketing purposes, including to analyse markets, develop marketing
strategies and to identify and develop products and services that may be
of interest to its customers.
When you become, or apply to become, a Dodo customer, Dodo collects
a range of other information that that it needs to assess your application
and manage your account(s). This includes:
 • Proof of identity information, including passport number, driver
    licence number or other government identifiers. We need this
    information to ensure our customer records are accurate and up-to-
    date. We also may be required to obtain proof of identity information
    by law. For example, we are required under the Telecommunications
    Act 1997 to obtain specified proof of identity information before
    providing certain mobile telephone services.
 • Financial and credit information, including credit history,
    employment history, remuneration details, bank account and
    credit card information, information about assets and income and
    details of relevant court judgments and bankruptcies. We need this
    information to assess creditworthiness and financial suitability of
    current and prospective customers.
 • Information about medical conditions and concession
    entitlement. We need this information to assess eligibility for
    concessional tariffs or other benefits that may be available with Dodo
    products or services. For example, in the case of electricity and gas,
    we may need information about medical conditions to ensure secure
    power supply for medical devices.
 • Information relating to occupancy. We may need information
    to establish that a customers has rights to occupy the property to
    which we provide services, and for this purpose may require copies
    of tenancy agreements, mortgage records or utility bills or supply
    records.
 • Information relating to change of name or status, which may
    include marriage certificates, death certificates and other official
    documentation. We may need this information where we are asked to
    close or transfer an account.
 • Employment information, including information about employment
    history including current and past employers. We may need this
    information to assess the financial position of a person who applies
    to become a Dodo customer.
 • Insurance information. In providing insurance products and
    services, we may need to collect information we need to assess the
    risks of providing insurance, including information relating to pre-
    existing conditions, claims history and previous insurance.
3.

 • Integrated Public Number Database (IPND). In providing
    telecommunications services, Dodo is required by law to collect
    certain personal information about you, including your name,
    address, telephone service number and other public number
    customer details, and to provide it to the operator of the IPND) for
    inclusion in the IPND. Information in the IPND is used to develop
    directories and to assist emergency service organisations.
    If your phone number is unlisted, your information will be
    marked accordingly in the IPND and its use and disclosure will be
    strictly controlled.
We also collect information about the way our customers use Dodo
products and services. This includes information about:
 • service usage (including energy consumption patterns, use of
    communications services, internet usages);
 • responses to offers made and/or promotions run by Dodo or its
    affiliates;
 • payment patterns and history; and
 • inquiries and complaints.
We collect information about our employees and prospective employees
for the purpose of making employment decisions and managing our
staff. We also collect information about suppliers, service providers,
agents and affiliates, and their staff, for the purposes of conducting our
day-to-day business activities.
How does Dodo collect personal information?
We collect personal information by various means and via various media,
depending on the particular business context.
We collect information about prospective customers both directly and
via our agents, service providers and affiliates. We may collect this
information:
 • when you make an inquiry at a Dodo kiosk, Dodo dealer or Dodo
    event;
 • through our door to door sales activities;
 • through our call centres;
 • through Dodo websites, or websites operated by Dodo’s affiliates;
 • through social media platforms such as Twitter and Facebook; and
 • through the purchase of marketing lists, databases and data
    aggregation services.
When you become or apply to become a Dodo customer, in addition to
collecting personal information directly from you, we may also collect
information about you from our agents and affiliates, credit reporting
agencies, your past and present employers, current service providers,
family members or associates and other third parties.
When you apply to become a Dodo customer, we will ask you to consent
to us collecting information from particular third parties. We will only
collect personal information from those parties if you consent. If you do
not consent, we may not be able to provide the service or product you
require. We are authorised to collect some personal information from
third parties under Privacy Law.
Dodo receives unsolicited personal information from time to time. In
accordance with its obligations under Privacy Law, Dodo will decide
whether it would have been permitted to solicit and collect that
information and if it would not have been, will destroy or de-identify the
information (provided it is lawful to do so).
                                                                         4.

What information will Dodo give you when it collects
personal information?
Dodo is required by Privacy Law to take reasonable steps to ensure
thatyou are made aware of certain information when it collects personal
information about you. For example, we are required to:
 • tell you which Dodo entity you are dealing with and how to contact it;
 • make sure you are aware that we have collected the information (if we
    collect it from a third party without your knowledge);
 • identify any law that authorises or requires collection of
    the information;
 • let you know the purposes for which we collect the information, the
    entities that the information is likely to be disclosed to and whether
    the information will be transferred outside Australia; and
 • tell you how to access our Privacy Policy and complaint handling
    procedures.
This Privacy Policy sets out this information in general terms. However,
where we collect personal information in relation to a particular product
or service, and the information we are required to provide is not likely
to be obvious from the circumstances, we usually provide the required
information in a ‘collection statement’. The way we do this will depend
on how you are dealing with us. For example:
 • When personal information is collected via the Dodo website or any
    affiliate website that Dodo may advertise on, a statement is displayed
    or a link provided to a statement that sets out the information we are
    required to provide.
 • A statement containing the required information is printed on the
    sign-up page of most of the standard forms we use to collect personal
    information.
 • When you deal with us on the telephone, this information is given to
    you by the operator or via a recorded message.
If we collect personal information about you from a third party, we take
reasonable steps to ensure you receive the information we are required
to provide. However, we may do this by requiring the third party to
provide the information, rather than us providing the information to you
directly.
We may also include information about our collection of personal
information in welcome packs, customer account statements, update
bulletins, notices and other documents we give to our customers.
Dodo’s use and disclosure of personal information
Where Dodo collects personal information for a particular purpose,
it may use and disclose the information for that purpose or another
purpose that is related to that purpose (or that is directly related to that
purpose in the case of sensitive information). For example:
 • Personal information collected from you for the purpose of
    establishing or managing an account may be used and disclosed
    for related purposes such as identity verification, credit checking,
    assessing entitlement to concessions, supplying and servicing
    a product, connecting and administering a service, billing and
    collection in relation to the service and investigating and rectifying
    complaints or faults.
 • Personal information collected for the purpose of establishing or
    managing an account may also be used for the purpose marketing
    of other Dodo products and services. Dodo may contact prospective,
    current or past customers about products and services (including
5.

    products not related to a product or service previously supplied). For
    example if we currently provide you with a telephone service, we may
    contact you with offers relating to electricity and gas services.
Dodo may use personal information about prospective, current and
past customers for the purpose of direct marketing of Dodo products
and services or those of other organisations. Direct marketing
communications may be sent via post, e-mail, telephone, door to door
canvassing, social media sites or other means. However:
 • Dodo will not use sensitive information for direct marketing purposes
    without your consent.
 • Unless you have provided consent, or we think it is impracticable to
    obtain your consent, Dodo will not use your personal information
    for direct marketing purposes where we have obtained the personal
    information from a third party, or we have collected it directly from
    you but believe that you would not reasonably expect the information
    to be used for direct marketing.
 • Whenever we communicate with you for direct marketing purposes,
    we will give you the opportunity to opt out of receiving further direct
    marketing communications from Dodo.
 • You may opt out of receiving direct marketing communications from
    Dodo at any time by contacting us at customerservice@dodo.com
    or calling 13 dodo (13 36 36).
 • If we use your personal information to facilitate direct marketing
    by other organisations on behalf of other organisations, you can
    ask us to provide the source of the information by contacting us at
    customerservice@dodo.com or calling 13 dodo (13 36 36).
Personal information about Dodo staff, agents, affiliates and service
providers is used and may be disclosed for the purpose of managing the
relationship with the staff member or other entity.
Dodo may disclose personal information about Dodo customers to a
range of third parties. For example, depending on the type of product
or service, Dodo may disclose customer information to a wholesaler or
other third party who provides or assists to provide the service.
 • For insurance products and services, Dodo provides personal
    information to our insurance principals and underwriters, namely
    Auto & General Services Pty Ltd and Auto & General Insurance
    Company Ltd.
 • For energy products and services, Dodo may disclose personal
    information collected for account management, provisioning
    and fault management purposes to the relevant electricity or
    gas distributor and to the operator of our billing and network
    management system Agility CIS System.
 • For electricity and gas services,         to the Energy and Water
    Ombudsmen (Victoria), Energy and          Water Ombudsmen (NSW),
    Energy and Water Ombudsmen               (Queensland) and Energy
    and Water Ombudsmen (South                Australia) (for complaint
    management purposes).
 • For telecommunications services, to the Telecommunications
    Industry Ombudsman (for complaint management purposes).
Dodo may disclose information to government agencies (such as
Centrelink) for the purpose of establishing or verifying eligibility for
concessions and similar entitlements.
Dodo may also disclose personal information for credit checking,
collection or credit reporting purposes to a credit reporting agency or
credit collection agency, in accordance with the requirements of the
Privacy Act 1988.
                                                                          6.

Personal information may also be disclosed to third party agents
and service providers who Dodo engages to assist in the provision of
products and services. These include:
 • sales agents and representatives;
 • organisations that process banking transactions;
 • organisations that process debt collection;
 • printers, mail distributors, couriers and dispatch centres;
 • call centres operated by entities outside the Dodo Group;
 • IT service providers and data managers;
 • legal, accounting, insurance and business advisory consultants
    services
Personal information Dodo obtains in connection with the provision
of telecommunications services may be disclosed in accordance
with requirements of the Telecommunications Act 1997 (Cth) and the
Telecommunications (Interception and Access) Act 1979 (Cth). This includes
disclosure:
 • to the Telecommunications Industry Ombudsman for the purpose of
    complaint management;
 • in connection with directory assistance, emergency service calls
    or other urgent services, and in particular to the operator of the
    Integrated Public Number Database (IPND) for inclusion in the IPND,
    including your name, address, telephone service number and other
    public number customer details, and to provide it. (Information in the
    IPND is used to develop directories and to assist emergency service
    organisations. If your phone number is unlisted, your information will
    be marked accordingly in the IPND and its use and disclosure will be
    strictly controlled.); and
 • to law enforcement agencies for law enforcement or security
    purposes; and
Personal information Dodo obtains in connection with the provision of
electricity and gas services may be disclosed in accordance with federal
and state based electricity and gas legislation and codes. This includes
disclosure:
 • to the various State based energy Ombudsmen identified above, for
    the purpose of complaint management;
 • in connection with electricity and gas safety cases or other urgent
    services; and
 • to law enforcement agencies for law enforcement or security
    purposes.
Dodo may also disclose personal information without consent as
authorised by privacy law for a range of other purposes, including:
 • where necessary to prevent or lessen a serious threat to health or
    safety;
 • for law enforcement or crime prevention purposes;
 • for the investigation of unlawful activity;
 • for location of missing persons; and
 • for use in legal proceedings or dispute resolution.
In situations other than those described above, Dodo will not disclose
personal information without the customer’s consent (although consent
may be implied).
7.

Is personal information disclosed outside
Australia?
Dodo discloses some personal information to persons or organisations
that are outside Australia.
 • Dodo’s customer service and marketing call centre operations
    are based in Manila, Philippines. Personal information about
    prospective, current and past customers is accessed by our Manila
    based staff for the purpose of sales and marketing, customer service,
    correspondence, provisioning, fault management and technical
    support activities.
 • Database and webhosting services provided to Dodo involve personal
    information being transferred to IT service providers based in India,
    Philippines, Singapore, New Zealand, the United Kingdom, Canada
    and the United States of America.
How does Dodo protect your personal
information?
Dodo recognises the importance of protecting your personal information
and of ensuring that it is complete, accurate, up-to-date and relevant.
When you call Dodo, we complete an ID check to verify your identity and
to check the details we hold about you are correct and to update them
if required. For some safety critical information, for example medical
information required to maintain secure power supply or ensure priority
assistance, we initiate checks on an annual basis.
We have documented processes for verifying personal information
collected for particular transactions, such as proof of occupancy, change
of occupier and priority assistance. Our staff are trained to properly
handle the different types of information they receive, particularly
sensitive information. We have quality assurance measures in place to
monitor calls to ensure that our processes are being followed.
While some of the personal information we collect is held in hardcopy
form, most personal information is stored in electronic databases.
We have extensive processes in place to ensure that our information
systems and files are kept secure from unauthorised access and
interference. These include:
 • System access is controlled by logins and different security levels.
    Access to customer information for all staff (including agents in our
    Manila call centre) is centrally controlled. Access requests must be
    supported by a request from senior management.
 • Access authorisation is layered and access authorisations are specific
    to the job function of each staff member. For example, staff with
    responsibility for fault management have no access to credit card
    information. Staff are only trained in areas of the system specific to
    the function of their job.
 • Functional restrictions apply. Remote access is only available to
    selected senior staff members. Measures are taken to prevent
    printing, copying or recording of customer information that can be
    accessed electronically. For example, call centre team members
    work in a paperless environment, cannot print information and are
    not permitted to have mobile phones or cameras on the call centre
    floor.
 • Account and system access and modification is logged to enable
    access or modification of any customer record by any staff member
    to be identified. Audits of access logs are conducted periodically.
 • Our employees undergo privacy and information security training
    on induction and are required to sign acknowledgements of their
    obligations in relation information security and appropriate use of
    our IT systems.
                                                                         8.

 • We have contractual arrangements in place with our agents, service
    providers and affiliates that require them to have comply with
    applicable privacy laws and Dodo privacy policies. Our contractual
    arrangements with third parties who are outside Australia are
    designed to ensure that personal information transferred to those
    parties is afforded the same level of protection as would apply to the
    information in Australia.
Can you access or correct personal
information Dodo holds about you?
You have a right to access personal information we hold about you. If
your request is particularly complex or requires detailed searching of our
records, there may be a cost to you in order for us to provide you with
this information.
If you believe there are errors in the information we hold about you, you
have a right to ask us to correct the information.
However, we are not required to provide access where we believe doing
so would:
 • prejudice law enforcement or crime prevention activities;
 • pose a serious threat to health or safety;
 • have an unreasonable impact on the privacy of other individuals;
 • prejudice Dodo in legal proceedings or negotiations with you;
 • reveal information connected with a commercially sensitive decision
    making process; or
 • be contrary to law.
If you wish to have access to information Dodo holds about you, you
should contact Dodo Customer Service. This includes information we
have sent on your behalf to the Integrated Public Number Database
(IPND). You are entitled to ask us to provide you with the details we have
provided about you to the IPND. You can do this by contacting Dodo
Customer Service and we will provide you with the information normally
within 20 Business days.
If you find any errors after you have received your information from us,
please let us know and we will make the corrections provided that any
changes are in line with IPND requirements. We will let you know if we
need further information from you, for example evidence of the correct
spelling of your name. Dodo does not charge you to access or correct
your information in the IPND.
Dealing with Dodo online
This Privacy Policy also applies to personal information that you email to
us, provide by using our website or provide via social media sites.
We store the Internet Protocol (IP) address of your computer when you
visit our site. This information is used only to create broad demographic
summaries of where our users come from. Our use of these IP addresses,
however, does not go so far as to identify the actual users of the site.
We collect personal information about the other websites that are
visited by computers that are used to visit our site. This information
may be aggregated to provide us with information about the types of
webpages and websites, or particular webpages and websites, visited by
computers that use our site.
Our website implements the use of data from your device(s) via cookies
and other identifiers (e.g. web beacons). This data is used to statistically
9.

monitor and analyse your use of our site and affiliated third party sites,
and we may tailor advertising or content based on your use of these
sites. However, unless we have obtained your express consent, we will
not use this data to personally identify you, and we will not share this
information with any third parties. If you wish to do so, you can opt-out
of sharing information about your use of this site or affiliate third party
sites by accessing the settings of your device or browser. Please note that
cookies and other identifiers are device and browser specific (i.e. you will
need to opt-out of each device / browser in order to completely opt-out).
Note that this privacy policy does not apply to, and Dodo is not
responsible for, the use of, or the protection of information provided to,
other websites linked to this website.
Complaints and further information
If you believe your privacy has been interfered with and wish to make
a complaint, please contact our Privacy Officer. The Privacy Officer will
investigate your complaint and notify you of the outcome.
If it appears from your complaint that there has been an interference with
privacy by a person other than Dodo, the Privacy Officer may discuss the
complaint with that person in an attempt to resolve it.
If you are dissatisfied with the outcome of your complaint, or you do not
receive a response to your complaint within 30 days, you may make a
complaint to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner
(OAIC). Complaints to the OAIC must be made in writing. Where possible,
complaints to the OAIC should be made through the online Privacy
Complaint form, available at www.oaic.gov.au/privacy/making-a-
privacy-complaint.
If you would like further information on this Privacy Policy or if you have
any concerns over the protection of your personal information, please
contact:
Privacy officer
Attention:     The Privacy Officer
Email:         privacy@dodo.com.au
Address:       PO BOX 631, Collins St West, Melbourne VIC 8007
                                                                         10.

Dodo Group of Companies
     PO BOX 631 Collins St West
        Melbourne VIC 8007
 13 dodo (13 36 36) www.dodo.com
       DOD_A0800_Terms_Booklet_02_2018
